Technical Executive and Leader in Emerging Technology

Executive Leadership | Technical Visionary | Innovate, Engineer, Scale

Technical innovation leader with executive level experience extending from hands-on engineering to global business implementation. I excel at building and leading business, technology, and product teams that deliver results in emerging technologies and drive the transformation into successful new products and digital solutions.

Career Highlights and Results

- Established the enterprise emerging technology & innovation practice responsible for go-to-market strategy, thought leadership, business development and sales enablement of custom digital solution for enterprise implementation.
- Thought leadership of enterprise emerging technology strategies, use case analysis, and enterprise scale implementation to C and VP level company leaders. Deliver business results through technical platforms such as cloud, artificial intelligence, machine learning, IoT, blockchain and mobile.
- Executive lead for Microsoft One Commercial Partner program. Developed co-sell ready business plan and go-to-market strategy for all custom digital solutions across Azure Intelligent Cloud offerings.
- Created and implemented the global team, DevOps model, product roadmap and development stack for web, mobile, cloud & machine learning development studio. Strategy included product ownership of all software products, IoT integration, data and analytics integration, artificial intelligence innovation, machine learning innovation and digital thought leadership.
- Led the creation of a mobile software solutions CoE organization of over 70 engineers and technical professionals including all recruiting, hiring, architectural standards, technology selection, development stack, automated QA, DevOps and software lifecycle management.
- Provide technical expertise and analysis for the Corporate Ventures investment team as subject matter expert for mobile, IoT and AR/VR technologies. Due diligence contribution for investment or buyout potential of startups and early stage companies.
- Established a strategic partnership with Xamarin to create a mobile solutions global practice that helped Microsoft to gain exposure in the mobile application development space through commercial engagements of Avanade.
- Led the team effort to architect, procure and globally deploy a scalable geographically redundant enterprise mobile device and app management platform. A major milestone within the company as it facilitated scalable global coverage for all mobile software and device services.
- Co-Founded remote monitoring and hardware/software systems startup specializing in highly scalable distributed monitoring and control technology for industrial IoT. Engineered multifaceted intellectual property roadmap resulting in 5 provisional patent applications and 2 full patent applications managed up to USPTO claims review.

Thought Leadership

- Microsoft Inspire Conference Speaker: Enterprise Blockchain Strategy
- Publication Author: Why Your Company Needs to do a Blockchain PoC in 2018
- Publication Author: Platform Approach for Mobile App Development
- AutoTech Council Speaker: Ridar Systems Connected Car Technology Innovation (IoT & Mobile)
- Xamarin Evolve Conf. Speaker: Establishing a World Class Mobile Software Engineering CoE
- Enterprise Mobility Summit Speaker: Ruggedized Mobile Devices for Field Employees
- Microsoft Innovation Summit Speaker: Engineering Cross Platform Mobile Solutions
- Software Technology Innovation Center Exhibit: Wearable Technology for Field Operations

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ArcTouch - Houston, TX 2017 - Present

Executive Vice President - Enterprise Solutions

As a member of the core executive team my responsibilities include defining the practice strategy, technology, and thought leadership of emerging technologies and digital solutions for enterprise clients. Thought leadership includes cloud technologies, IoT, artificial intelligence, machine learning, blockchain, and mobile apps.

- Established the enterprise emerging technology & innovation practice responsible for thought leadership, go-to-market strategy and business development of custom digital solution for enterprise implementation. Practice focus is based on a devotion to customer success by advancing their business with emerging technology implementations.
- Provide executive thought leadership to C and VP level technology leaders to identify disruptive and transformational business opportunities where emerging technologies can deliver results through competitive business advantage and market share growth.
- Lead the strategy and channel partnership business relationship with Microsoft One Commercial Partner program to
 accelerate business development and sales opportunity growth across global Fortune 500 clients. Developed co-sell
 ready business plan and go-to-market strategy for all custom digital solutions across Azure Intelligent Cloud offerings.
- Lead enterprise commercial engagements and direct relationship management as a trusted advisor to C and VP level corporate leadership. Negotiate business relationships, solution development contractual agreements and long-term technical partnership arrangements.
- Execute Digital Immersion workshops to Fortune 500 leaders to showcase emerging technology opportunities.
- Collaborating cross-functionally with colleagues and partners to create and deliver market facing programs and executive technology briefings in one-to-many and one-on-one settings.
- Core Technologies: Microsoft Azure, AWS, machine learning, artificial intelligence, blockchain, IoT, mobile apps

Schlumberger - Houston, TX

2014 - 2017

Director of Mobility Solutions

As a member of the global IT Strategy and Management team my leadership includes defining the global strategy, technology, and thought leadership for all aspects of the enterprise digital transformation. Thought leadership includes mobile, IoT, artificial intelligence, machine learning, blockchain and cloud technologies.

- Defined, implemented and led the global strategy for a world class mobile apps and software digital transformation model. The strategy includes the creation of an enterprise mobility solutions team, including full end to end product definition, mobile app development and dev ops capabilities.
 - **Result**: Conceived and executed a multi-year mobile transformation strategy and roadmap for the global enterprise, including the core technology stack, architecture, UX, QA and DevOps.
- Defined the team structure and grew the Mobility Solutions CoE from 1 to 70 full-time employees in less than 15 months. Team is a combination of North America, South America and India resources, all of which are direct hires.
 - Result: Highly coordinated and focused effort allowed us to shorten the onboarding process, hire the top 10% of the applicant pool and accelerating the development team scaling cycle.
- By implementing an internal startup team mentality, the product definition and software engineering cycle was scaled to full DevOps leveraging Agile/Scrum in an autonomous Squad structure to drive product roadmap, UX/UI design, engineering, QA, UAT, and deployment of over 15 iOS and Android apps.
- Identified the need for global offshore facilities in order to implement a high capacity agile based DevOps software engineering team.
 - o **Result:** Startup and operation of highly successful Pune Innovation and Technology Center that is now an internal model for scaling a world class software engineering team culture.
- Lead and foster joint partnerships with industry leading technology companies and service providers, such as, Apple, IBM, Accenture, Microsoft, Mobile Iron, Xamarin, and Samsung.
- Implemented a platform based software engineering approach with a "mobile first" initiative which focuses on user centric design think methodology, agile and dev ops for scalable global deployments.
 - o Result: In the first 6 months of operation lead the delivery of multiple full feature native mobile apps for

iOS and Android all developed on the Xamarin platform highly leveraging the shared C# code base, RESTful APIs, cloud based infrastructure.

Core Technologies: iOS, Objective C, xCode, Android, C#, Xamarin, ASP.Net Visual Studio, MS-SQL, Jira, MSSQL, Jenkins, Google Cloud, Microsoft Azure, AWS, RESTful APIs, JSON, XAML, MVC architecture.

Avanade - Seattle, WA 2013 - 2014

Global Cross Platform Mobility Lead

Avanade is a joint venture held by Accenture and Microsoft.

- Provide business and technical leadership as the Mobility Solutions Lead to the regional business units throughout the world. Develop and execute the go to market strategy for Avanade's core mobile technologies including Windows, iOS and Android.
 - Result: Through my leadership contribution, Avanade was awarded Microsoft Mobility Partner of the Year for 2014.
- Providing technical leadership to the business development executives by leading C-level technical thought leadership, client discovery workshops and solution architecture reviews as the technical subject matter expert.
 - o **Result:** Team was awarded several multi-million dollar mobility projects which included complete backend and mobile interface architecture, UX design, development, change management and deployment.

Stratopy -Houston, TX 2010 - 2013

Vice President of Engineering & Innovation

Technical Co-Founder and executive team member of a project based startup for the development of client specific mobile applications. Direct responsibility included leading and executing all software engineering as well as direct architecture and coding of iOS, Android and server side code.

- As VP of Engineered I work jointly with the VP of Product to architect and implemented the core product specifications which were used as the platform for all mobile application development projects.
- Led the engineering staff to define all technical product direction and architecture. Hands on coding of iOS, Android and HTML mobile apps including server-side code. Architected, designed, coded, tested, and deployed over 75 iOS and Android app with supporting RESTful API's, SQL databases and cloud technologies.
- Acted as primary technical lead to customers, partners, investors and board members. Maintained ultimate
 accountability for every product delivery whether core product technology or custom applications and systems
 integration projects.
- Provide daily project leadership and hands on participation architecture, code reviews, UI design, and schedule/resource/budget management.
- Prepared the pitch deck to tell the company's story to help any prospective buyer understand our product, team, customers, revenue and strategic value. Established criteria to determine how we would evaluate potential offers.

Biomatix Systems - Houston, TX

2004 - 2010

IoT and mobile tech startup focused on remote monitoring/control systems with expertise in aquatics automation

Chief Technology Officer

Led and participated in all aspects of engineering and design of proprietary electronics, software, and product development for complete line of automation components. Ensure growth by crafting strategic national marketing plan based on extensive research, establishing relationships with distributors and beta test partners, and negotiating / outsourcing manufacturing. Manage multiple patent applications. Technical Co-Founder

- Led all research and development, design, engineering, and manufacturing of proprietary electronic automation systems. Developed core hardware and software system architecture including functional requirements, electronics, firmware, remote communications software, and mechanical packaging.
 - o **Result**: Company successfully engineered, manufactured, and beta tested complete aquatic automation system, established presence as technology and product leader, and actively sold product nationwide.
- Direct hands-on engineering of electronics and software systems in a research and development mode and scaling to full production units. Daily bench level work to develop the product from the circuit board level to a finished consumer product.

- Architected and developed all firmware and software including bit level programming of Pic microprocessor and peripheral chips. Engineered all circuitry including board architecture, chip selection, schematic design, board production and final assembly.
- Negotiated joint business ventures for company startup funding and developed business plan comprised of product development model, technology, market positioning, intellectual property protection, budgetary planning, operations planning, and corporate growth staffing requirements. Pitched company to investors and technology partners, conducted extensive planning and strategy meetings with partners and Board of Directors, developed initial prototype, and filed provisional patents for technology.
 - o **Result:** formed company with initial funding commitment of \$1 MM to engineer, beta test, and create production units of the hardware and software technology.
- Established detailed multi-year intellectual property road map. Wrote and submitted 5 provisional patent applications to protect companies core technologies. Consolidated and further submitted 2 full patent applications and managed through claims review with USPTO.
- Core Technology: C, C++, C#, ASP.NET, Visual Studio, PHP, MySQL, MS-SQL, JavaScript, RESTful, JSON, XAML, MVC architecture, MPLabs, PIC-Microchip, Eagle PCB.

EDUCATION & CREDENTIALS

Graduate Studies, Master of Science, Mechanical Engineering UNIVERSITY OF ALABAMA, Tuscaloosa, AL

Bachelor of Science, Mechanical Engineering LAMAR UNIVERSITY, Beaumont, TX

Associate of Science, Applied Sciences, Computer Drafting Technology Lamar University, Beaumont, TX

Leadership and Executive Management Certification

Rice University - Graduate School of Business Management, Houston, TX

Entrepreneurship and Start-up Business Management Certification

Rice University - Graduate School of Business Management, Houston, TX

Board of Directors

Blue Cure Foundation

Chief Technical Advisor

Ridar Systems - Connect car technology startup in IoT and mobile

Chief Technical Advisor

Loyalopolis - Loyalty program startup in mobile marketing

Chief Technical Advisor

Kid Care Years - Childcare facility review and rating startup